welcome to meditating which on brevity
we live stream every weekday morning at
9:30 a.m. Eastern Time with Monday's
alternating between a lesson day a new
lesson Dharma day and a review of the
whole ecology practices in PI a day for
previous lessons and sits see the
description in this video I suggest
doing the first lesson right away then
start joining us every day and to do a
new lesson every Saturday or Sunday and
that will you integrate and catch up
with us while being able to participate
almost immediately in the Sangha I would
request that you please like this stream
to increase visibility on YouTube the
YouTube search algorithm so that I can
reach as many people as possible I'm
trying to help as many people as
possible right now as I mentioned there
are QA at the end of every session but
those q and a's please limit them to the
ecology of practice the course that
we're all along together the questions
have been truly wonderful and I
appreciate them deeply for more general
encompassing questions please join me
today at 3 p.m. live streamed on YouTube
for my general Q&A and we do one of
those every third Friday at 3 p.m.
Eastern Time
so I think that's everything we need in
order to get started and so please get
your basic posture going set your phones
on do not disturb and we will begin when
I say be good be good
[Music]
slowly come out to be a practice trying
as best you can to integrate what you
cultivated in your practice with your
everyday consciousness cognition
character and communitas perhaps by
reciting the five promises tears
we have time for other questions this is
from Kelly Meyers
Logan Kelly coming from a practice of
body scamming great vodka I'm not
familiar with it but I understand body
scanning I feel myself slipping into the
same pitfalls I encountered in that
practice and then finding that route can
you distinguish these two techniques for
me so there is a sense in which the
routing is a body scanning but one of
the things that the routing and this
comes out in the term routing emphasizes
is it's not just a scanning process or a
sensitization process it is also a deep
stabilization process and this is why
the downward movement and the releasing
and draining and then the deep sense of
connectedness and routing into the earth
is an essential poem component one of
the pitfalls I see maybe this is one of
the pitfalls you didn't who you weren't
specific or what the pitfalls were but
one of the pitfalls that people often
get into but the bonney's scan is they
get the sensitization but they also they
get energized and things start racing
because the the sense of groundedness
and stability they become very sort of
ethereal and so it's very important to
not just have the alertness of the
warrior but also to have the deep
stillness of the mountain and that's why
the process culminates in the sinking
into the earth the sensing the grounding
the sense of how the supports and
nourishes us reminding again the Buddha
touching the earth when he's achieving
enlightenment like that we are all
deeply embodied and embedded so perhaps
that's a particular pitfall you were
mentioning
another pitfall people often get with
the body skin is they they are oriented
to sort of picking up on sensations of
relaxation if they're they focus on
those and then that can lead to a deep
kind of the kind of relaxation that is
generally conducive to that sort of warm
fuzziness that is often mistaken for the
penetrating presence of mindfulness
that's why in the rooting exercise I
taught you
it was emphasized that you're trying to
let that area come to expression with
whatever sensations are wanting or
imminent and want to be become more
explicit and articulated in your
awareness and so that also shifts the
orientation of people who sort of
enjoying their bodies and body scan
we're in the routing is you're actually
putting your awareness in service of the
body allowing it to more dialogic ly
connect and express and inform and
potentially transform you so those are
three differences entry and how it helps
to address three kind of pitfalls I've
encountered trying to pay attention to
getting lost and then delt donating if I
can move on to the next step or booty
also getting lost in thought and losing
my place in the process yes so very much
that's the first pitfall that I talked
about so doing it in the sequence and
and that this is very much a draining
right and that you're not trying to get
into some state of completeness that you
if this area is completely relaxed
completely released that's not what
we're doing we're trying to get into
right relationship not perfection and
those are not the same thing and then
again the emphasis on that this whole
process is moving towards a culmination
in roundedness connectedness service to
the body letting it speak
so try and see if that is a helpful RIA
orientation for you Kelly
Liu quest I've been repeating day eight
for six days as I'm still taking maybe
eight to take 10 minutes to Center
really can flow my being overly
perfectionist or should I stay with this
part until it feels right I would say it
probably is right enough or good enough
don't worry about how long it takes of
it if it takes you about eight to 10
minutes for a while do that I strongly
recommend you move on now you move on
because as you move on and you start
learning the practices that build on
that those will become more properly and
appropriately like a background it but
integrated with the new practices and
they'll be less sort of focal and you'll
you'll be less tempted towards a
possible perfectionism so I think you're
doing it good enough don't and move on I
strongly recommend that here at Kroger
hi Carol it's good to see you again your
question yesterday was much appreciated
today while doing that I when I got to
someone I'm in conflict with what came
up was an image of the devil a monster
to be afraid of and I realized I see in
almost everyone I interact with am I
crazy no you're not crazy at all
is it okay to do matter towards that
image is it normal to start to have a
lot of religious imagery come up if you
had a religious background with imagery
coming up is very normal
you're not mad or anything like that
part of what is being ends sometimes
when stuff first comes up it almost
always comes up symbolically in an
imaginal fashion but we even have this
language we tend to demonize other
people when we're in conflict with them
and so what is being shown to you in a
very helpful manner is actually that
there's a demonic projection going on
there and then what you have to do is do
Metta towards them until you recognize
we realize their humanity which is not
the same thing as thinking that they're
wonderful or beautiful but this is what
I
talking about that the goal of meta is
ultimately reciprocal opening to make we
take this as if it is the easiest thing
in the world but right and genuinely
recognizing other people's humanity and
being in were right relationship to
their humanity to their personhood which
is not perfect it's not morally
wonderful but it is important and do
right and we have to be in right
relationship to it so very much
religious imagery will come up if you
had a religious upbringing I speak from
experience and pay attention to this
myth of poetic way of speaking sort of
this myth or poetic way this an
imaginable way of is often a way in
which things that are normally held in
unconsciously or that we're not seeing
that are biasing our attention first
come into far more conscious awareness
so take this as a gift and hopefully if
you relate to it appropriately that will
help you to become more explicitly aware
of the way in which there's projection
going on towards that person the oubli a
rouble sharing experience Thank You Dean
yesterday I connected the movement form
or is it movement from self-willed to
God's will twelve steps with movement
from having to the being loaded the
meditative experience excellent that's
fantastic so though when Dean just
shared with us and thank you for doing
that that's what I need that's when that
happens and you can tell that your life
is becoming more coherent deep and
opening when you get that kind of
transformative insight it's an
existential insight connecting the
movement from self will to God well from
the 12 steps here's one practice that
he's right engaged in and then here's
another one to having being removed from
the having to be mode so there's a
practice in his life and there's a
product and they resonate with each
other that's what I'm talking about that
that's that that's the
a to see if you're making progress on
the path thank you Dan for sharing that
I was wonderful purnima hi Karima
instead of using the Train I looked at
the sky cloudy and noticed patches of
blue expanding and that's where I focus
the clouds are all of my thoughts the
blue is clarity and pieces.this okay I
think I'm only getting part of your
question do you mean like instead of the
train of thought I'm looking you look at
the stuff that's fine the the sky in the
clouds is also a traditional metaphor
used I use the Train because it connects
with the metaphor of train of thought
and it tends to have a little bit more
of that sense of power and overwhelming
speed that I thought to have but if the
clouds and the sky work for you that's
also a traditional image that's great as
long as you don't as long as you want
sort of getting really heavy and just
sort of move right so as long as what
you said is the case that you're getting
a lot of clarity and you and that you've
got it so the thing about the sky is
make sure you have a sense that there is
a lot that still needs that there's a
lot that it's still undisclosed remember
ultimately what you're getting into you
is an inexhaustible field that affords a
continual movement of inquiring
mindfulness so excellent questions again
today and I hope my answers were helpful
and will afford you some understanding
and encouragement thank you very much
for joining as I said these questions
and the sharing thanks especially to me
are really really beneficial for all of
us including myself I want to thank my
dear friend and Tecna Mei Jamar he was
working miracles this morning before we
even got set up he's just did another
thing to improve the signal strength and
the reliability he's always there like a
faceless forging things right in a way
that will be marvelous and of course I
want to thank my son Jason who is always
here coping with unexpected contingent
things in the environment
making things happen my beloved son is
always his work is always appreciated
please subscribe to this channel to be
notified of the next video you will also
find links to the lecture series
awakening phenomena crisis and to the
logo series voices with for baking where
these issues are explored in more depth
more overarching integration and set
into a more encompassing framework that
is trying to address both perennial
problems and our particular historical
situations invite others who might to
benefit so by others who might benefit
from this series as I said I'm not
driving anything from this I am trying
my very best to help as many people as I
possibly can right now breath is here
pleasure of doubt please join the
discourse River to chat with others the
link is in the description it's my
understanding that some people are
meeting before we meet in the sit and
doing the movement practice together
that's great the more this Sangha takes
on a life of its own the better and I
know that you also meet after the
sitting and sometimes the Alexio Divina
sometimes get into dialogue and then
there's a just a more encompassing
community the era it's my understanding
that I think Jordan Hall my good friend
Jordan all was there doing Q&A last
night this is all amazing it's vital and
vibrant and please go there minded we do
this every weekday morning so there will
be no session tomorrow or Sunday we do
it every weekday morning at 9:30 Eastern
Time final reminder today 3 P 3 p.m.
live stream we'll have the general the
more general Q&A please remember that
continuity of practice is more important
than a quantity of practice there is no
enemy worse than your own mind and body
no friend no ally no true companion on
the pathway as great as your own mind
and body be lamps unto yourself and to
each other
take good care I'll see you all on
Monday or perhaps this afternoon at 3
p.m.
goodbye